Hello friends, my name is Abhishek Gand.
Welcome to my channel Invest Show. Friends, today
in this video we will cover
about a plan of Aditya Billa in
which you can take a policy in the name of your child
and can avail the income benefit in it for a very long period
and you
also get a lump sum amount on maturity
which you can use for your child's higher education or his
marriage. Yes
friends, I am talking about Aditya Billa
's Ayush Nishchay Plan. This is an
excellent plan in which the company has launched four to
five variants which you
can choose according to your requirement. So let's move ahead
and cover that product
in detail.
Before moving ahead in the video, friends, if you have come to our channel for the
first time, then please subscribe to our
channel so that all of you keep getting such great
information. And at last, if you like the
video, then like and share it.
Your every like motivates us to
make such information videos. Let's go
and cover the product in detail. First of all, let's
talk about the entry age. In this product, the
minimum  The minimum maturity age of the life insured is 30 days and the
maximum is 55 years. If I
talk about the maturity age of the life insured, then the
minimum maturity age should be 18
years and the maximum is 85 years. If I
talk about the premium payment and policy term, then
in the screen we have
given different premium payment terms and
policy term which you get according to your variant.
If I talk about the premium amount, then
here the minimum premium
is 30000 and there is no maximum limit,
you can invest as much as your pocket can answer.
Next is the
minimum sum assured, then the minimum sum assured is 2.1
lakh and if I talk about the maximum sum assured, then the
underwriting team will decide
how much maximum sum assured you can get. If
I talk about the benefit payment frequency, then
here you
can take the benefit monthly, quarterly, half yearly or yearly.
Next is the date benefit, so here we have
given a table, whichever is higher, the
company will give you the death benefit.  The next benefit it provides is the
staggered death benefit
option. Here, the company
also gives you the option of staggered death benefit, in which the
nominee is also given the option to take the death benefit
amount in an installment,
if the nominee does not want it in installments.
Now, let's talk about riders. The
first rider that is available is the
accidental death benefit rider. In this, the company
says that
if tomorrow the insured
person dies by accident under the accidental death benefit scheme, then
his nominee is given the sum insured of that accidental rider. The only
condition in this is
that the
minimum age of the insured person should be 18 years. Next is the
critical illness rider. Here again, if the
insured person suffers from any critical illness, then the
company provides 100% off-cuts cover,
and here the company has given the condition
that the minimum period should be 30 days.  There should be a survival period
and the minimum age of the insured person should be
18 years. Next is Surgical Care
Rider. So here, if the insured person
goes for surgery due to any illness or accidental injury, then the
company provides him any
benefit for the
treatment of that particular illness or
accidental injury. But the condition of the company
here is that there should be 24 hours hospitalization
and minimum age should be 18
years. Next is Hospital Care Rider. So,
here the company provides a separate daily cash benefit
to the insured person. There should be a
minimum 24 hours hospitalization
and minimum age should be 18 years.
Next is Waiver of Premium. So, here
all the future premiums of the insured person are
waived if the
insured person gets any critical illness
or because of any  Due to
accidental injury, he gets disabled
or dies. Here the
condition of the company is that the
age of the insured person should be below 18 years.
So friends, in this way we have
covered the basic details and riders. Now let's talk about the
variants. The company has
given you five variants here. The
first variant is Level Income with
Lump Sum Benefit. Here the company
provides you an income for a certain period
and after that it provides you a lump sum benefit. Let us
understand this as an example.
For example, if the person is 30 years old and he is paying a
premium of ₹1 lakh per year and the
premium payment term is 10 years and the
policy term is 40 years and the
deferment period taken there is zero, which means that
he will start getting income from the first year. So
here in income benefit, he gets ₹36300
from the first year itself
for the next 40 years and
separate benefit at maturity.  He gets Rs 14 lakh from this.
If the person dies within 40 years,
then whatever death benefit is there is
given to him and the policy
closes there. The second option which is available is
Level Income with Enhanced Sum
Benefit. So here again the company
provides you an income benefit for a certain period
and whatever maturity remains, he
gets more. So here again we
see from the example, if a 30 year old person is
paying a premium of Rs 1 lakh, the
premium payment term is 10 years, the policy term is 40 years,
again the deferment period is
zero, then he will get Rs 3425 in income benefit
for the next 40 years and
he will get Rs 20 lakh in maturity benefit. So
friends, here if you see,
in the first and second plan,
approximately
Rs 2000000 is getting less in income benefit but the maturity
benefit increases by approximately Rs 6 lakh.  Yes
again, in this also you get death
benefit, next is increasing
income at 5 per simple analysis in every five
years with sum benefit. So here the company is
increasing your income benefit every 5 years at the rate of 5 per simple
analysis and is also providing you maturity benefit separately. Let us
understand this as an example. For example again, if a
person is 30 years old and is paying ₹1 lakh premium,
his policy term is 40 years,
his premium term is 10 years and the
deferment period is again zero, then
his income benefit
starts from ₹33800 and in every five
years his income benefit increases by ₹5.
So if I look at the overall income benefit,
how much income benefit he gets in the next 40 years, then
he gets approximately ₹15 lakh
8600 as an income benefit.
Along with this, he is given Rs. 14 lakh separately at maturity.
In this also the company is providing you death
benefit. If tomorrow the
insured person dies within 40 years,
then whatever death benefit is there is
given to his nominee. Next is
level income with return of premium. So here the
company provides you income benefit
and at the maturity whatever premium you have
paid is refunded to you. Let us
understand this as an example. For example, if a
person is 30 years old and is paying Rs. 1 lakh premium.
Premium payment term is 10 years.
Policy term is 40 years. Deferment period
is zero. Income, he will get Rs. 38700 for the
next 40 years and maturity benefit is the
premium paid to him, that is, Rs. 1 lakh
premium paid for 10 years is returned to him.
In this also the company is providing you death
benefit. Next is
income benefit only. So in this variant  In this, the
company only provides you income benefit, there is no
separate maturity benefit. Let us
understand this with an example.
If a 30-year-old person is
paying a premium of ₹1 lakh for the next 10 years
and the policy term is 40 years and the
deferment period is zero, then he
gets an income benefit of ₹45,000. There is
no maturity period here. If the person
dies, whatever his death benefit is,
it is given to his nominee. So
here, if a person wants higher income
but does not want any maturity benefit, then he can
choose the fifth option.
So friends, in this way we have
covered all the things of the product. I hope you
liked the information. We have
given the brochure of the product in the description link. If you
want, you can go through it further.
Also, let me tell you friends, we deal in the products of all the big
health insurance, life insurance,
mutual fund companies
and also provide pan-India sales and service. So,
if you  If you
want to buy any of these products by joining us, then you
can contact on the number given below.
Along with this, we provide a paid consultancy
at a very nominal fee. So if you
want to take our expert advice, then
we also provide that service.
If you have any small query related to health insurance
or life insurance or mutual fund,
then you can ask us in the comment box.
We will try to answer your questions. If you
like the video, then like,
share and subscribe. Thank you.